

Contacts

olena.pobehailo@gmail.com

LinkedIn

GitHub

<u>Telegram</u>

Lviv, Ukraine

Portfolio link

Tech skills

- HTML5
- CSS3
- SASS
- JavaScript
- React
- Redux
- Node.js
- MongoDB
- PostgreSQL
- REST API
- TypeScript
- Next.js

Soft skills

- Strong analytical thinking
- Willingness to learn
- Attentive to details and precise
- Solution-focused thinking
- · Calm and determined

Languages

English - intermediate Ukrainian - native

Olena Pobehailo

Junior Full Stack developer

Having worked for many years as a lead engineer specializing in metal science, I've become proficient in solving various tasks quickly and efficiently, analyzing large amounts of information, paying close attention to detail, working effectively in a team, maintaining composure under time constraints, and always seeking new knowledge.

Currently, I am a motivated Full Stack developer, that is committed to lifelong learning.

PROJECT EXPERIENCE

Contacts REST API

API for managing contacts. It includes endpoints for CRUD operations, user authentication, user registration, login, logout, and avatar management.

Tech: Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB

Code, Live page

LearnLingo

An app for an online language teaching company. Users filter teachers by language, level, rates, and add favorites. Firebase handles auth.

Tech: React, Firebase, Styled components

Code, Live page

Car Rental Services

Test project. Car rental app - Users can filter different car rental options by make, hourly price and mileage and add to favorites. Backend - MockAPI.

Tech: React, Firebase, Styled components

Code, Live page

Movie Search App

The TMDB Movie Search App is a web tool using the TMDB API, enabling users to find information about movies, actors, and reviews on The Movie Database platform.

Tech: JavaScript, React, Redux, Styled components

Code, Live page

Pixabay Image Search App

The Pixabay Image Search App is an application that searches for images. Users enter a search query, and the app displays relevant images.

Tech: JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML, SCSS

Code, Live page

Cucina di Catherina

A responsively designed e-commerce website. We at GoIT built this project in collaboration with six other students. I successfully created a modal window.

Tech: HTML, SASS, Responsive/Adaptive design, BEM methodology, JavaScript Code. Live page

WebStudio

The project implemented responsive/adoptive design for the best possible website viewing experience using HTML and SASS.

Tech: HTML, SASS, Responsive/Adaptive design, BEM methodology.

Code, Live page

WORK EXPERIENCE

Lead engineer, engineer of metallographic laboratory

Azovstal Iron and Steel Works, Mariupol (2013-2022)

Conducted comprehensive metallographic investigations to:

- Determine the root causes of component failures.
- Identify the underlying reasons for defects.
- Evaluate and determine the optimal variant of technology.

Engineer of heat treatment laboratory

Azovstal Iron and Steel Works, Mariupol (1995-2013)

Analyzed extensive datasets to:

- Develop of processing techniques for new products.
- Adjust existing technologies for optimization.
- Modify chemical compositions to achieve specific quality standards.

EDUCATION

IT School GoIT

2022 - 2024

Fullstack Developer

Pre-Azov State Technical University, Mariupol

Metal Science, Technology, and Equipment for Heat Treatment of Metals